# Vaibhav Gogte

2260 Hayward St., Ann Arbor, MI 48109 | vgogte@umich.edu | +1 (352) 870-7970 | http://web.eecs.umich.edu/~vgogte

### **Research Interests**

My current research focuses on designing runtime systems and hardware architecture for emerging byte-addressable persistent memories. Specifically, I have designed memory models in high-level languages and processor architectures that allow easier persistent memory programming, and built software systems that use persistent memories as faster storage.

### Education

• Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science and Engineering M.S. Computer Science and Engineering

*University of Michigan - Ann Arbor* (GPA: 4.0/4.0) Thesis: Runtime Systems for Persistent Memories

Advisor: Prof. Thomas F. Wenisch

• B.E. (Hons.), Electrical & Electronics Engineering
Birla Institute of Technology & Science - Pilani, India (GPA: 8.92/10.0)

Sept 2014 – Dec 2019 (expected) Sept 2014 – Apr 2016

Aug 2007 - May 2011

# Experience

Graduate Student Research Assistant, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

Sept 2014 - Present

- Strand Persistency: In this work, I proposed hardware primitives to minimally constrain ordering on persistent memory operations. I designed compiler mechanisms that map persistency semantics in high-level languages to the hardware primitives. This work achieves up to 1.97× speedup over existing hardware ordering mechanisms.
- Persistency for Synchronization-Free Regions: In this work, I proposed persistency semantics that guarantee failure
  atomicity of synchronization-free regions, program regions delimited by synchronization operations. Our approach
  provides clear semantics for post-failure state by extending sequentially consistent guarantees to the recovery code.
- Language-Level Persistency: This project defines an acquire-release persistency model as an extension to the C++11 memory model. The persistency model relaxes the ordering constraints while accessing recoverable data structures in persistent memory-enabled systems.
- OS-based Wear Management for Persistent Memories: Emerging persistent memories suffer from a limited write endurance. I designed an application-transparent wear-management technique in Linux kernel that detects the disparity in the write accesses and performs targeted page migrations to manage wear of the persistent memory.
- Hardware Accelerator for Regular Expressions: In this work, I designed a stall-free hardware accelerator for matching regular expressions at a scan rate offered by modern DDRs. I built a compiler toolchain in C++ that transforms the regular expressions to the binary used by our hardware design.
- **Programmable and Energy-Efficient 3D Convolution Engine**: I developed a hardware accelerator that improves data locality when fetching 3D images from the main memory. The convolution engine overlaps the processing of locally cached image pixels with the fetching of a new set of pixel data from the main memory.

#### **Performance and Capacity Research Intern**, Facebook, Menlo Park

May 2019 – Aug 2019

• Persistent Memory Usecases for Facebook Applications: In this work, I designed persistent memory-aware block cache for RocksDB, a key-value store application. I evaluated several RocksDB usecases in Facebook applications to show throughput and latency improvement due to the persistent memory-aware cache.

Research Intern, Microsoft Research, Redmond

May 2018 – Aug 2018, May 2017 – Aug 2017

- Low-cost and Predictable Storage Management for Persistent Memories: The access latency of persistent memories, storage features and modern networks are a few microseconds. In this work, I proposed low-cost and predictable storage by offloading their management to the ARM-based commodity SoC device attached to the host over PCIe.
- Load-balancing in Catapult architecture: I extended the routing and transport layer in the Catapult architecture to dynamically balance query load in the FPGA-enabled servers. The proposed mechanism monitors the response latency and manages the load offered by the FPGAs.

**Senior Design Engineer**, Texas Instruments, Bangalore

Jul 2011 – Jul 2014

• **Design of microprocessor subsystems based on ARM processors**: I designed power management, protocol converters, and interrupt controllers for dual-core microprocessor subsystems based on ARM Cortex A9, A7, and M4 processors.

# **Teaching Experience**

Graduate Student Instructor, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

• Parallel Computer Architecture (EECS 570)

Jan 2017 - May 2017

• Introduction to Logic Design (EECS 270)

Jan 2015 – May 2015

### **Peer-Reviewed Publications**

• StrandWeaver: Relaxed Persist Ordering Using Strand Persistency (Under review)

V. Gogte, W. Wang, S. Diestelhorst, P. M. Chen, S. Narayanasamy, and T. F. Wenisch.

• Language Support for Memory Persistency

A. Kolli, V. Gogte, A. Saidi, S. Diestelhorst, W. Wang, P. M. Chen, S. Narayanasamy, and T. F. Wenisch. Top Picks of the 2019 Computer Architecture Conferences (**Top Picks**). Jun 2019.

• Software Wear Management for Persistent Memories

**V. Gogte**, W. Wang, S. Diestelhorst, A. Kolli, P. M. Chen, S. Narayanasamy, and T. F. Wenisch. 17th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (**FAST**). Feb 2019.

• Persistency for Synchronization-Free Regions

V. Gogte, W. Wang, S. Diestelhorst, S. Narayanasamy, P. M. Chen, and T. F. Wenisch. 39th ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI). Apr 2018.

• Language-Level Persistency

A. Kolli, **V. Gogte**, A. Saidi, S. Diestelhorst, P. M. Chen, S. Narayanasamy, and T. F. Wenisch. 44th Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture (**ISCA**). Jun 2017.

• HARE: Hardware Accelerator for Regular Expressions

**V. Gogte**, A. Kolli, M. J. Cafarella, L. D'Antoni, T. F. Wenisch. 49th International Symposium on Microarchitecture (**MICRO**). Oct 2016.

### Workshops

• Strand Persistency

**V. Gogte**, W. Wang, S. Diestelhorst, P. M. Chen, S. Narayanasamy, and T. F. Wenisch. 10th Annual Non-Volatile Memories Workshop (**NVMW**). Mar 2019.

• Failure-Atomic Synchronization-Free Regions

**V. Gogte**, W. Wang, S. Diestelhorst, S. Narayanasamy, P. M. Chen, and T. F. Wenisch. 9th Annual Non-Volatile Memories Workshop (**NVMW**). Mar 2018.

• TARP: Translating Acquire-Release Persistency

A. Kolli, **V. Gogte**, A. Saidi, S. Diestelhorst, P. M. Chen, S. Narayanasamy, and T. F. Wenisch. 8th Annual Non-Volatile Memories Workshop (**NVMW**). Mar 2017.

#### **Patents**

• Instruction ordering

P. M. Chen, S. Diestelhorst, V. Gogte, S. Narayanasamy, W. Wang, T. F. Wenisch. (Patent Pending)

• Detecting at least one predetermined pattern in stream of symbols

M. J. Cafarella, V. Gogte, T. F. Wenisch. (*Patent Pending*)

#### **Press**

- Persistency for Synchronization-Free Regions, ARM Research, 2018. Link.
- Honorable mentions for service as EECS 570 graduate student instructor, 2017. Link.
- Baking Specialization into Hardware Cools CPU Concerns, Next Platform, 2016. Link.

### **Service**

- Shadow Program Committee Member for EuroSys'19
- Reviewer for IEEE CAL'19, TOMPECS'19, TACO'18 and TODAES'16 journals

### **Technical Skills**

- Languages: C, C++, Verilog HDL
- Software and Design Tools: LLVM, Murphi, DynamoRio, Git, Latex
- Architectural simulators: Gem5, Booksim